Joshua McNabb

Full-Stack Software Developer

- ⊠ joshuamcnabb1995@gmail.com
- (780) 385-8977
- Calgary, Canada
- https://github.com/JoshuaM1995

INTRODUCTION

I am a passionate software developer with \sim 5 years of professional industry experience. My personal philosophy is to always strive to learn something new.

Outside of work I enjoy listening to music, playing video games, longboarding and hiking.

</> </>

HTML

CSS (LESS, SCSS/SASS, CSS-in-JS)

JavaScript (TypeScript)

Node (Express/Koa, NestJS, Prisma, Knex)

PostgreSQL

React (Next.js, ChakraUI)

React Native (Expo, NativeBase)

Docker

CI/CD (Github Actions, Gitlab Pipelines, Kubernetes, Pulumi)

Jira (Standardized workflows, Automation)

EDUCATION

Object Oriented Software Development

SAIT

03/2018 - 10/2018 | Calgary, Canada

Courses

- Web Applications
 - HTML/CSS/JavaScript
- C#

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Full-Stack Software Developer

Launchcode 🛮

11/2020 - 08/2023 | Calgary, Canada

- Worked with Lead Developer on Oil & Gas MVP, then became project lead after two months
 - Successfully delivered project to the client after one year, reducing the time they spent entering data in the field by 50%
- Worked with two other developers on a Healthcare MVP for Cisco
 - Helped migrate away from legacy internal tools toward open-source software
 - Migrated to Monorepo architecture using Turborepo
 - Created a feature for caregivers to create tasks for individuals they're managing, with dynamic inputs (instructions, location, step-by-step, etc.)
 - Created a recurring task system using previous knowledge with iCal Recurrence Rule standard
 - Worked on both React web application and React Native mobile application

Junior Full-Stack Software Developer

Routeique 🛮

10/2018 - 11/2020 | Calgary, Canada

- Built a recurring order system using PHP (Laravel), JavaScript and MySQL. Integrated iCal Recurrence Rule specification.
- Created a dynamic form builder using Object-Oriented Programming principles
- Helped migrate legacy frontend from jQuery to React using best practices
- Redesigned marketing website for a healthcare company, making it completely mobile-responsive

PROJECTS

Competitor Fox

09/2022 - 08/2023

- Created frontend with React
- Created backend with NestJS, using best practices to allow scalability
- Integrated Puppeteer to scrape websites
- Implemented cron and queue separate from API to allow horizontal scaling
- Continuous Integration using Github Actions to built, test and lint code
- Automated DigitalOcean deployments using Github Actions and Docker

Spotalytics

2018

• Created frontend using React and TypeScript

- Built a Windows desktop application
- Java
 - Built an Android application with a group of 5
- Databases
- Linux
- Networking

• Integrated with Spotify's API to pull account statistics and recommend new music

Crossroads Parts Software

2016 – 2016

- Created my first web application using HTML, CSS (Bootstrap) and jQuery as well as JavaScript DataTables
- Added ability to edit multiple table rows/cells for quick and efficient data entry, reducing time it took to record inventory from two weeks to one week